When your collecting iron stone we talked about different patterns the different types of iron stone collect what I wanted to just show you today is that iron stone base is the heavy weight to it and it comes in different forms.
This one in particular is the white base iron stone which you will see this has a little bit of flow blue and a little of luster on it.
This is an iron stone base but it's the flow blue patterns that are on here this is early 19th century and you'll find that this is just a flow blue pattern but you'll find this in brown transfer.
Which is an iron heavy base also you'll find it in a red transfer the earlier the iron stone base is heavier base to it.
The other pieces that you find with iron stone base if the mulberry patterns a lot of those English wares made in the early to mid late 19th century you'll find that they have an iron stone base.
There made by the same a lot of these pieces are made by similar companies in England during the same period but they would produce the blue as well as the mulberry at the same time using the bases which are similar.
You might even find in iron stone a pattern that's the same as flow blue and you can find the same pattern in mulberry so there's a lot of different examples of iron stone bases that are used.
You can find a plain iron stone we also talked about LaMoush and bases to the LaMouch pattern that's iron stone also with lots of different patterns.
You can also find just a plain iron stone here that's made by a number of different companies in England these are all examples of heavy earth and ware that was made in 19th century into the 20th century.
They are very collectible and it all is very subjective it's what you find appealing so these are just a few example for you to look at before you start collecting.